to post this guidance work.
It is very much experience and a lot of reflections
from these events and we see that there are wishes
at very many different levels within rescue service
And to get guidance for their role.
This has very much ruled us in the disposition of this guidance
and it has become very extensive for that reason
that we want as well as a part that will fit each
With different backgrounds and needs.
After all, we have in the run -up of this guidance work,
When we have looked at ...
this internationally and we have really searched
And preferably we probably would have just been able to translate to Swedish something
As someone else had done that had been good,
But unfortunately it was not there.
So we've received help
and we announced a study to obtain computational data
For all the questions we need answers to.
So, we can have a sense of how long jet flames become,
We can have a feeling for how far splits fly
and how far away you get your hearing injured and so on
and how dangerous gas cloudsxplosions are in tunnels,
But we can't determine this just because of gut feeling,
For this we have to base on something.
Otherwise it is not credible for MSB to publish a guide
If we have nothing to build on.
So this we have tried to do with
and calculations that we have been able to pick home
from the scientific world.
What do you do with this then
Yes, this must be accepted by all actors.
We have therefore started a broad collaboration
by anchoring this guidance.
Of course, this is nothing that one shakes out of the cuff arm
Without us having picked up the academy with us.
We have Lund University of Technology and Umeå University
Which has helped us a lot in the traffic accident area before.
After all, we have people with testing experience from RISE.
when accidents get in their inner cities.
That is why we have brought with us Greater Stockholm of course,
Which has a lot of experience and Uppsala fire defense as well.
They have a little more resources and they can help us a little easier
than maybe a very small rescue service, so it is not
to try to withhold the problems of small rescue services
And challenges.
When it comes to the energy bakes, we have mixed in the energy industry
through its industry organizations primarily and it is hydrogen Sweden
and Energigas Sweden with which we capture them,
But we have also taken in Gasum when it comes to LNG,
Because they have more technical knowledge about their systems then.
Other authorities are also important that we have with us.
FOI we have given the assignment for external monitoring.
We have balled some questions with them.
The Swedish Transport Administration is very affected when this happens
In our infrastructure in tunnels and so on
That we have them with us, so that we do not miss important aspects.
The Swedish Transport Agency that approves vehicles and has that vehicle knowledge
As we need them too are important
To get statistics and so on from.
Then this is a lot of work environment issues,